

Summary

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer adept in front-end and back-end solutions. I've worked with an assortment of technologies including Javascript, React, HTML/CSS, SQL and more. I am also able to effectively self-manage during independent work as well as collaborate on projects and lead teams to complete tasks.

Employment

From Lab 2 Fulfillment

Remote Jan. 2023 to Current

Software Engineer

- Mainly using React, JS, Node, and Express, I created several new full-stack apps to my employers specifications.
- Used Agile workflow to collaborate with colleagues and git for source control.
- Analyzed code written by others in several languages to find and fix bugs or update code base.
- Deployed apps using Google Cloud Repositories and Cloud run to deploy Docker containers onto the web.

Various Employers

Beamsville, ON 2022 to Current

Freelance Web Developer

- Built, updated, and deployed several websites and web applications for various employers.
- Used a variety of coding languages to deliver clean, functional code in a timely manner.

Grand Niagara

Niagara Falls, ON 2015 to 2022

Maintenance Supervisor

- Managed a team of employees and led the completion of various projects.
- Collaborated with management to increase worker efficiency in certain areas by up to 25%.

Concentrix

Niagara Falls, ON 2020 to 2020

Technical Support Advisor

- Handled a variety of customer requests and dealt with any new issues as they arose.
- Adapted and learned constantly for continued efficiency on calls.

Projects

Simpli

Simpli is a team-based project tracking productivity app. Projects are mapped through a list of deliverables, each containing its own list of tasks.

Front-end: React, JS, CSS, HTML

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL

Interview Scheduler

Interview Scheduler is a Single Page Application built for creating and tracking student interviews.

Front-end: React JS CSS HTML

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL

Test: Jest, Storybook, Cypress

Resource Haven

Resource Haven allows learners to save learning resources (i.e. urls) like tutorials, blogs and videos in a central place that is publicly available to any user.

Front-end: HTML, CSS, JS, EJS, Sass, JQuery

Back-end: Node, Express, SQL

WOGSA Redesign

Contract for a redesign that turned an out of date website into a modern single-page responsive site. Stack: HTML, CSS, JS, JQuery

Ongoing Property Booking Project

Contract to create a single page booking app for a property owned by the client.

Front-end: React, JS, CSS, HTML

Back-End: Node, Express, PostgreSQL

Volunteering

Oueen's Model Parliament · Coordinator Ottawa

2018 to 2019

Queen's Alma Mater Society · Campaign Aide Kingston, ON

2018 to 2019

Rotary Club · Volunteer Grimsby, ON

2012 to 2015

Contact

nealeptaylor@gmail.com

nealetaylor.com

905-329-6340

♥ Toronto

in nealeptaylor

○ NealePT

Skills

LANGUAGES

Javascript

Ruby

HTML

CSS

FRAMEWORKS, LIBRARIES

NodeJS

ReactJS

Rails Ajax

Express

EJS

JQuery

Bootstrap

Sass

SYSTEMS, DATABASES

PostgreSQL

Git

MySQL

Docker

Google Cloud

TESTING

Mocha

Chai Jest

Cypress

Storybook

Education

Lighthouse Labs

2022

2021

Diploma Full-Stack Web Development

Juno College Front-End Web Development Course

BA (Honours) Political Studies

Queen's University

2015 to 2019